# OSAMA ABDELRAHMAN

Senior Mobile Application Developer **Experienced Full Stack Developer** Junior Data Scientist

O UAE, Abu Dhabi.

+971-586623199

@Osamaabdalla.com

# **SUMMARY**

I have seven years of experience in Full-stack Web development and Cross-platform mobile apps especially using React native. I also spent two years practicing Data Science during my master's degree including six months as a Data Scientist.

# **OBJECTIVE**

To enhance my professional skills, capabilities, and knowledge in an organization that recognizes the value of hard work and trusts me with responsibilities and challenges.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Created and contributed in more than +46 cross-platform mobile applications for both Android and iPhone, with more than 84 web applications and admin dashboards. Moreover I contributed in 6 real projects in Data Science field.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Data Science and Analytics Malaysia, 2020 Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM).

Study areas:

- Machine Learning
- Business Intelligence & Decision Analytics
- Multimodal Information Retrieval
- Enabling Technologies, Infrastructures For Big Data
- Big Data Storage And Management
- Research, Consultancy, And Professional Skills
- Consumer Behavioural And Social Media Analytics
- Principles & Practices Of Data Science & Analytics and Visualisation

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sudan, 2012

Omdurman Islamic University (OIU)

Study areas:

- Operations Research and Artificial Intelligence
- Web. Programming and Software Engineering
- Computer Networks and Expert Systems
- Information System Management and Security & Analysis
- Relational Databases and Data Structure

# **SKILLS**

**	Cross Platform Mobile Apps .7yrs
***	Front-end Development 7yrs
*	Back-end Development 6yrs
*	Machine Learning 2yrs
*	Data Science 2yrs
**	Deep learning 1yrs

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

**	HTML (8 Years) 5/5
*	CSS (8 Years) 5/5
*	JavaScript (7 Years) 4/5
*	TypeScript (6 Years) 4/5
*	PHP (6 Years) 4/5
*	Python (2 Years) 3/5
*	Angular V1&2 (2 Years) 3/5

#### **DATABASES**

**	MySQL (7 Years) 4/5
*	MongoDB (4 Years) 4/5

# **FRAMEWORKS**

*	React Native (5 Years) 4/5
**	Meteor (4 Years) 4/5
*	React (4 Years) 4/5
*	Ionic (3 Years) 4/5
**	Laravel (3 Years)

#### TOOLS

VSCode	Spider	GitHub
Terminal	Anaconda	Tableau
XCode	Postman	Jupyter

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Mobile Application Developer

Nov 2020 - Nov 2021

#### **ACCENTURE**

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Create functional design deliverables (including page-flow, business logic, validations, etc.
- Manage requirement confirmation & design workshops.
- Create/Enhance Mobile applications.
- Perform System Testing on the web-based application.
- Support SIT / UAT testing & to perform bug fix.
- Perform code build and deployment of the completed codes into the development and testing environment.

#### Data scientist, Internship

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

#### MOLEX (MALAYSIA) SDN. BHD

Penang, Malaysia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Develop and deploy statistical and machine learning models for data analysis to discover any hidden patterns.
- Collaborate with product management and engineering departments to understand the assembly production needs and devise possible data science solutions.
- Communicate results and ideas to key decision-makers.
- Implement new statistical methodologies as needed for specific models or analysis to ensure the final product quality.
- Optimize joint development efforts through appropriate database use and project design.
- The deployed models results showed a significant improvement in the products quality and a feasible reduction in the rejection rates.

#### Full Stack Developer

Apr 2018 - Jan 2019

#### TOWARD LEADERSHIP

Medina. Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Developing front end website architecture for clients.
- Designing user interactions on web pages.
- Developing back end website applications.
- Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring responsiveness of applications.
- Working alongside graphic designers in the company for web designs.
- Designing and developing APIs between Front and Back ends.
- Communicating with the projects manger to meet the consumer needs.

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

MAC Windows Linux

#### CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

WordPress | OpenCart | Django

#### DEV OPS

AWS DigitalOcean OpenStack

#### OTHER SKILLS

AJAX JQuery Node Js Redux

RESTfull NPM Agile Scrum

#### **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH ...... AdvancedARABIC ..... Native

#### **WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS**

Website: Osamaabdalla.com
GitHub: @Osamaabdalla

Linkedin: @Osamaabdallacom

#### **PARTICIPATIONS**

Participated in the record event of the most participants in a Hackathon is 2,950 was achieved by Saudi federation for cyber security, programming, and drones Saudi Arabia, which was verified in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, on August 2018. Our participation involve two mobile applications to help in improving Hajjij (pilgrims) journey while they are in the holy places

# <u>INTERESTS</u>

Video Games => Flight simulation

#### Web & Mobile Apps Developer

Nov 2015 - Mar 2018

#### MARKETING-IT SOLUTIONS

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating and maintaining customers' mobile applications.
- Developing dashboards for mobile applications.
- Developing front and back end website applications.
- Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring compatibility of the mobile applications.
- Working alongside managers and graphic designers in the company for web and mobile apps designs.
- Designing and developing APIs between Dashboards and Apps.

Web Developer Oct 2013 - Oct 2015

#### **HOWISTART**

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating and maintaining website applications and admins dashboards.
- Developing back end for customers web applications.
- Creating servers and databases based on customer's needs.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for websites pages.
- Ensuring compatibility of the websites applications.
- Creating and managing Amazon web services for websites.
- Monitor and maintain any possible vulnerabilities to avoid hacking.
- Managing websites security and as a result the company got Trustwave certificate to offer credit card payments through their website.
- Integrate the payment gateways such as 2checkout, Stirpe, and Paypal.

# **PROJECTS**

## Sakrobe mobile application

Feb 2014 - Dec 2019

Website: https://sakrobe.com

Sakrobe is a mobile application that I have created during my freelancing time to link home maintenance service providers with their customers, for both Android and iPhone platforms, it took about two years to deploy the final stable version, the final achievements as below:

- The App had more than 250K active installs during that time.
- More than 400 daily orders with up to thousand during weekends.
- More than 650 home maintenance service provider registered.
- More than 84K active customer accounts monthly.
- 21 maintenance services provided through the App.

#### Anfas-sharqya mobile application

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

Website: <a href="https://anfas-sharqya.com">https://anfas-sharqya.com</a>

Anfas-sharqya is a mobile application that I have created during my freelancing time for a local store jewelry to sell their products to their customers for both Android and iPhone platforms, the final achievements as below:

- The App had more than 40K active installs during that time.
- More than 60 daily orders with up to 200 during weekends.
- More than 1200 products sold through the app.
- More than 2K active customer accounts monthly.

#### Bmbrella mobile application

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

Website: http://bmbrella.com

Bmbrella is a multi-purpose application created as social media platform to make the users communicate with others and at the same time giving them the ability to sell their services or products.